Guide to the Thomas Moore papers, 1804-1847 MS 015
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Thomas Moore papers
1804-1847
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852
MS 015
4 Linear Feet (3 boxes, 1 oversize box)
Chiefly letters of Moore; together with correspondence, poems, engravings, clippings, and photos. Includes material relating to Wilfred S. Dowden, editor of Moore's letters. Correspondents include William Lisle Bowles, Lord and Lady Holland, Thomas Longman, Ellen Moore, James Power, Lord John Russell, Sir Walter Scott, and Mary Shelley.
Biographical Note
The Irish poet Thomas Moore was born in Dublin on May 28, 1779. His earliest poetic compositions appeared in Anthologia Hibernica during the years 1792-1795. He briefly studied law in London, and other than a brief foray into parliamentary politics, the primary focuses of his life were poetry and the cultivation of aristocratic society. Irish Melodies is his most lasting claim to fame, and this work has been credited with both preserving and popularising the numerous ancient Irish airs which form its core.
Scope and Contents
The papers, 1804-1847, of Thomas Moore consist of letters, photographs and engravings, newspaper articles and clippings, poems and correspondence.
The letters are arranged chronologically and divided into numbered and unnumbered originals and copies. The numbered letters, originals and copies are those included in the two volume edition, T he Letters of Thomas Moore, edited by Wilfred S. Dowden (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1964.) Of the 1,323 numbered letters contained in the book, this collection has 223; 156 originals and 67 copies. The numbering on this list corresponds to the numbering system devised by Dr. Dowden. The unnumbered letters are those not included in The Letters of Thomas Moore, but which span the same time period and include both original letters and copies.
The letters are arranged in the following manner: I. Numbered Originals, II. Unnumbered Originals, III. Numbered Copies, and IV. Unnumbered Copies. Numbered originals consist of those original letters contained in Dowden's work. Unnumbered originals include letters written by Moore, letter fragments and miscellaneous envelopes addressed or signed by Moore, some printed material about Moore and letters to Moore. Numbered copies consists of photocopies of letters written by Moore and included in the published edition. Among a variety of items found in the unnumbered copies are copies of letters letters written by Moore, copies of letters written to Moore, correspondence written concerning Moore and his works, and correspondence concerning the purchase of Moore material and excerpts from catalogues advertising Moore material. In addition to the numbered and unnumbered catagories mentioned above, there is a Commonplace Book contained in a black notebook filled with photocopies of pages in Moore's handwriting.
Box 1 contains only numbered originals; box 2 contains numbered originals and unnumbered originals, numbered and unnumbered copies, microfilm, and the Commonplace Book.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Boxes 1-3 stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586. Box 4 located onsite at Woodson Research Center in the small manuscript section.
Index Terms
Subjects
Irish poetry; Poetry
Places
Ireland
Subjects (Persons)
Holland, Elizabeth Vassall Fox, Lady, 1770-1845; Holland, Henry Richard Vassall, Baron, 1773-1840; Longman, Thomas Norton, 1771-1842; Moore, Ellen, -1846; Bowles, William Lisle, 1762-1850; Dowden, Wilfred S. (Wilfred Sellars), 1917-; Shelley, Mary Wollstonecraft, 1797-1851; Power, James, 1766-1836; Russell, John Russell, Earl, 1792-1878; Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832
- Series I: Numbered originals, 252185 (Box 1)
  - Thomas Moore to John Erskine Douglas, [1804] June 28; NUMBER (DOWDEN) [89]; 252342; ALS
  - T.M. to J. McMahon, [116]; 252341; ALS
  - T.M. to James Carpenter, [1810 February or March]; [172]; 252340; ALS
  - T.M. to Edward S. Foss, [1811 September 18]; [196]; 252339; ALS
  - T.M. to Thomas Longman, [1811]; [212]; 252338; ALS
  - T.M. to James Carpenter, [1812 April 14]; [226]; 252337; ALS
  - T.M. to J. Taylor, [1812 May]; [231]; 252336; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, [1812 December 30]; [276]; 252335; ALS
  - T.M. to James Carpenter, [1813 January]; [288]; 252334; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, [1813 March]; [303]; 252333; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1813 September 13; [338]; 252332; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Smith, 1814 February 21; [364]; 252331; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1814 July 4; [384]; 252330; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1815 March 3; [424]; 252329; ALS
  - T.M. to John Erskine Douglas, 1816 January 13; [455]; 252328; ALS
  - T.M. to John Erskine Douglas, 1817 June 2; [501]; 252327; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, [1817 October]; [516]; 252326; ALS
  - T.M. to William L. Bowles, [1818 October]; [567]; 252325; ALS
  - T.M. to William L. Bowles, [1819 April]; [575]; 252324; ALS
  - T.M. to Captain Macdonald, 1819 July 2; [576]; 252323; ALS
  - T.M. to Longman and Co., 1821 January 27; [596]; 252322; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1821 April 27; [597]; 252321; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1821 April 28; [598]; 252320; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Locke, Hughes, and Co., 1821 July 21; [600]; 252319; ALS
  - T.M. to Douglas, [1821 August]; [603]; 252318; ALS
  - T.M. to William Perry, 1821 September 12; [604]; 252317; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, [1821 October 18]; [609]; 252316; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Belcher, 1821 October 27; [610]; 252315; ALS
  - T.M. to Wadham Locke, [1822]; [627]; 252314; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Holland, [1824 April 2]; [647]; 252313; ALS
  - T.M. to Lupton Relfe, 1824 August 1; [652]; 252312; ALS
  - T.M. to Thomas Phillips, 1824 September 15; [654]; 252311; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1824 October 11; [657]; 252310; ALS
  - T.M. to Col. Francis Doyle, 1824 November 5; [658]; 252309; ALS
  - T.M. to William Murray, 1824 November 13; [660]; 252308; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1824 December 31; [661]; 252307; ALS
  - T.M. to Wadham Locke, [1824]; [662]; 252306; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1825 March 29; [664]; 252305; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1825 October or November]; [675]; 252304; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Fletcher, 1825 November 10; [677]; 252303; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [684]; 252302; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [686]; 252301; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Crumpe, [1826 January]; [691]; 252300; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1826 February]; [693]; 252299; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1826 March 27; [696]; 252298; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Francis Jeffrey, 1826 April 29; [700]; 252297; ALS
  - T.M. to Edward Moore, 1826 June 11; [702]; 252296; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, [1826 November 10]; [707]; 252295; ALS
  - T.M. to Henry R. Bishop, [1826 November]; [710]; 252294; ALS
  - T.M. to A. Spottiswode, 1827 May 30; [721]; 252293; ALS
  - T.M. to J.R. Planche, 1827 July 23; [726]; 252292; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1827 July 30; [727]; 252291; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1828 February 1; [761]; 252290; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord John Russell, [1828 February or March]; [766]; 252289; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1828 May 12; [785]; 252288; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1829 January 11; [804]; 252287; ALS
  - T.M. to Owen Rees, 1829 March 16; [810]; 252286; ALS
  - T.M. to Owen Rees, 1829 April 26; [828]; 252285; ALS
  - T.M. to Richard Milliken, 1829 July 21; [846]; 252284; ALS
  - T.M. to John Wilson Croker, [1829 July or August]; [847]; 252283; ALS
  - T.M. to Samuel Clark, 1829 August 4; [852]; 252282; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Sandon, [1829 August]; [859]; 252281; ALS
  - T.M. to John Wilson Croker, 1829 November 30; [877]; 252280; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, [894]; 252279; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1830 January 2; [906]; 252278; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1830 March 7; [923]; 252277; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1830 June 14; [929]; 252276; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, [1830 June]; [931]; 252275; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1830 December 12; [948]; 252274; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Wm. L. Bowles, 1832 March 24; [997]; 252273; ALS
  - T.M. to Peter Legh, 1832 August 3; [1011]; 252272; ALS
  - T.M. to Alicia Lefanu, 1832 August 7; [1012]; 252271; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Mereweather, 1832 October 7; [1016]; 252270; ALS
  - T.M. to E. R. Moran, 1832 November 6; [1019]; 252269; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Stanley, 1832 November 29; [1022]; 252268; ALS
  - T.M. to Samuel Rogers, 1832 December 9; [1024]; 252267; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. L. Bowles, 1833 May 7; [1029]; 252266; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1833 May or June]; [1031]; 252265; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1833 June 2; [1032]; 252264; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Kerry, 1833 June 12; [1033]; 252263; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1833 November 13; [1040]; 252262; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Kerry, 1834 January 6; [1048]; 252261; ALS
  - T.M. to Henry Bishop, 1834 February 26; [1052]; 252260; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Blessington, 1834 June 12; [1057]; 252259; ALS
  - T.M. to J. Crookes, 1834 December 9; [1062]; 252258; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, [1064]; 252257; ALS
  - T.M. to Peter Cunningham, 1835 March 8; [1068]; 252256; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Windsor, 1835 March 17; [1069]; 252255; ALS
  - T.M. to A. Hayward, [1835] March 21; [1070]; 252254; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1835 May 23; [1074]; 252253; ALS
  - T.M. to Locke, Hughes and Saunders, 1835 May 30; [1075]; 252252; ALS
  - T.M. to Col. Houlton, [1835 June]; [1078]; 252251; ALS
  - T.M. to Thomas Hume, 1835 October 18; [1082]; 252250; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Mrs. Wm. L. Bowles, [1836 July or August]; [1091]; 252249; ALS
  - T. M. to George R. Ward, 1836 October 21; [1095]; 252248; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Ward, 1837 May 3; [1103]; 252247; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1130]; 252246; ALS
  - T. M. to John Richards, 1838 April 22; [1141]; 252245; ALS
  - T. M. to Dr. Black, 1838 April 22; [1142]; 252244; ALS
  - T. M. to John Richardson, 1838 July 8; [1146]; 252243; ALS
  - T. M. to Edward Moxon, [1838] July; [1148]; 252242; ALS
  - T. M. to Thomas Longman, 1839 February 20; [1159]; 252241; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1839 September 13; [1169]; 252240; ALS
  - T. M. to Samuel Rogers, 1840 July 24; [1185]; 252239; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1840 August 10; [1188]; 252238; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Money, 1840 November 14; [1196]; 252237; ALS
  - T. M. to Lord John Russell, 1841 September 11; [1211]; 252236; ALS
  - T. M. to Edward Moxon, 1842 January 2; [1213]; 252235; ALS
  - T. M. to Lord John Russell, 1842 April 17; [1215]; 252234; ALS
  - T. M. to John Hancock, 1842 April 20; [1216]; 252233; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. S. C. Hall, 1842 May 31; [1218]; 252232; ALS
  - T. M. to Thomas Longman, [1843 April 3]; [1228]; 252231; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Addison, 1843 May 14; [1229]; 252230; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1844 January 5; [1232]; 252229; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Wright, 1844 April 29; [1233]; 252228; ALS
  - T. M. to Rev. Dr. George Croly, 1845 July 11; [1241]; 252227; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1846 February 27; [1243]; 252226; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Mrs. Holland, 1846 June 15; [1244]; 252225; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1846 November 7; [1248]; 252224; ALS
  - T. M. to Edward Moxon, 1847 January 26; [1249]; 252223; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, n.d.; [1254]; 252222; ALS
  - T. M. to Lady Holland, [1255]; 252221; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; [1256]; 252220; ALS
  - T. M. to Mrs. Starkey, n.d.; [1257]; 252219; ALS
  - T. M. to Rev. Henry Drury, n.d.; [1259]; 252218; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Spencer, n.d.; [1262]; 252217; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; [1264]; 252216; ALS
  - T. M. to Mary Shelley, n.d.; [1265]; 252215; ALS
  - T. M. to Sir Gore Ouseley, n.d.; [1266]; 252214; ALS
  - T. M. to John Bennett, n.d.; [1267]; 252213; ALS
  - T. M. to A. Hayward, n.d.; [1268]; 252212; ALS
  - T. M. to Dr. Holland, [1269]; 252211; ALS
  - T. M. to Col. Hamilton, n.d.; [1270]; 252210; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Locke, n.d.; [1271]; 252209; ALS
  - T. M. to James Carpenter, n.d.; [1272]; 252208; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; [1286]; 252207; ALS
  - T. M. to Mr. Hardman, n.d.; [1288]; 252206; ALS
  - T. M. to Sydney Orven, n.d.; [1296]; 252205; ALS
  - T. M. to Thomas Longman, n.d.; [1297]; 252204; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d., [1298]; 252203
  - Addressee Unknown, [1817 July 8]; [1299]; 252202; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Sir James Mackintosh, [1819 July]; [1300]; 252201; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1820]; [1302]; 252200; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1820]; [1303]; 252199; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1820]; [1304]; 252198; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Wm. L. Bowles, [1824]; [1306]; 252197; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1827]; [1307]; 252196; ALS
  - T. M. to Frederick Byng, [1833]; [1309]; 252195; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, 1836 February 18; [1310]; 252194; ALS
  - T. M. to Miss Coutts, 1840 March 8; [1311]; 252193; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, [1840 June 17]; [1312]; 252192; ALS
  - T. M. to Thomas Longman, 1840 July 14; [1313]; 252191; ALS
  - T. M. to Sydney Smith, 1843 August 7; [1314]; 252190; ALS
  - T. M. to Robert Howe Gould, 1845 July 1; [1315]; 252189; ALS
  - T. M. to Robert Howe Gould, [1846] June 12; [1316]; 252188; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, n.d.; [1317]; 252187; ALS
  - T. M. to Wm. L. Bowles, n.d.; [1318]; 252186; ALS
- Series II: Unnumbered originals, 252016 (Box 1)
  - Thomas Moore to Mr. C. Flack, Esq., [1810]; 252184; ALS
  - T. M. to Lady Asgill, [1811]; 252183; ALS
  - T. M. to [John] Douglas, 1813 November 1; 252182; ALS
  - T. M. to James Power, 1814 July; 252181; ALS
  - T. M. to [James] Power, 1814 November 21; 252180; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Mrs. Power, 1815 January 31; 252179; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Power, 1816 February 8; 252178; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Power, 1816 July 16; 252177; ALS
  - T.M. to M.A. Shee, 1817 February 14; 252176; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Shee, 1818 April 3; 252175; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1819 March 4; 252174; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1821 August 21; 252173; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1821 November 29; 252172; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Power, 1822 November 17; 252171; ALS
  - T.M. to Frederick Byng, 1823 February 13; 252170; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1824 February 15; 252169; ALS
  - T.M. to [Joseph Bounelen], 1824 April 16; 252168; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1824 June 30; 252167; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1824 December 31; 252166; ANS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1825 May 10; 252165; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Holland, 1825 May 11; 252164; ALS
  - T.M. to Cosmo Orme, 1825 July 31; 252163; ALS
  - T.M. to Dr. Madden, 1825 October 10; 252162; ALS
  - T.M. to Robert Balmanno, 1826 April 3; 252161; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1826 May 25; 252160; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Magrath, 1827 February 5; 252159; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1827 March 30; 252158; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1827 May 28; 252157; ALS
  - Wm. Murray, 1827 June 30; 252156; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Locke, [1827 November 25]; 252155; ALS
  - T.M. to Drury, 1828 January 14; 252154; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1828 April 20; 252153; ALS
  - T.M. to Dudley Cortello, 1828 October 18; 252152; ALS
  - T.M. to [Francis] Chauntry, 1828 November 23; 252151; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1829 January 10; 252150; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Holland, 1829 February 23; 252149; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Byng, 1829 March 23; 252148; ALS
  - T.M. to Wm. Murray, 1830 June 6; 252147; ALS
  - T.M. to Rev. Kenrick, 1830 August 30; 252146; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Morgan, [1830 August]; 252145; ALS
  - T.M. to Sir Charles Morgan, 1830 September 20; 252144; ALS
  - T.M. to John Murray, 1830 [November] 17; 252143; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1830 December 30; 252142; ALS
  - T.M. to Longman and Co., 1831 April 10; 252141; ADS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1831 May 13; 252140; ALS
  - T.M. to Madame Money, 1831 August 15; 252139; ALS
  - T.M. to Longman and Co., 1831 October 11; 252138; ADS
  - T.M. to W.L. Bowles, 1832 January 8; 252137; ALS
  - T.M. to Captain Marryat, 1832 May 27; 252136; ALS
  - T.M. to Rev. Meylin, 1832 July 30; 252135; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1832 September 5; 252134; AN
  - T.M. to Mr. Power, [1832 October 16]; 252133; ALS
  - T.M. to Dr. Griffin, 1832 November 1; 252132; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Locke, Hughes and Co., 1833 June 25; 252131; ADS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1833 October 25; 252130; ALS
  - T.M. to Christopher Moore, 1834 February 6; 252129; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Blessington, 1834 [August 20]; 252128; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Hughes, [1834]; 252127; ALS
  - T.M. to Thomas Moore, Jr., 1835 June 6; 252126; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Serdan, 1835 December 15; 252125; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1836 January 22; 252124; ALS
  - T.M. to [Henry] Mereweather, 1836 April 8; 252123; ALS
  - T.M. to T. Macrone, 1836 August 17; 252122; ALS
  - T.M. to Irving, [1836]; 252121; ALS
  - T.M. to General Fuller, 1837 June 20; 252120; ALS
  - T.M. to General Fuller, [1837 June 22]; 252119; ALS
  - T.M. to Thomas Longman, 1837 August 23; 252118; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Lefanu, [1837] October 2; 252117; ALS
  - T.M. to John Bennett, 1837 December 1; 252116; ALS
  - T.M. to Spring Rice, 1837 December 3; 252115; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1838 March 2; 252114; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1838 March 11; 252113; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1838 July 29; 252112; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Crumpe, [1839] January 2; 252111; AL
  - T.M. to [James Corry], 1839 March 8,9; 252110; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Jones, 1839 August 2; 252109; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Holland, 1839 November 15; 252108; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1839 December 6; 252107; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1840 February 5; 252106; ANS
  - Thomas Moore to Messrs. Locke, Hughes and Co., 1840 July 12; 252105; ADS
  - T.M. to Mr. Eastlake, 1840 August 11; 252104; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1840 November 2; 252103; ALS
  - T.M. to Locke, Hughes and Co., 1840 November 17; 252102; ADS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1841 March 24; 252101; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Hughes, 1841 March 31; 252100; ALS
  - T.M. to Barbara, [1841] June 17; 252099; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1841 July 27; 252098; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1841 August; 252097; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1841 November 10; 252096; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1842 March 30; 252095; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1842 December 9; 252094; ALS
  - T.M. [to James Kirby], 1843 September 5; 252093; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Hall, 1844 August 23; 252092; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Lefanu, 1845 February 23; 252091; ALS
  - T.M. to Locke, Hughes and Co., 1846 January 26; 252090; ADS
  - T.M. to Hughes, Locke and Co., 1846 January 26; 252089; ADS
  - T.M. to Hughes, Locke and Co., 1846 February 9; 252088; ADS
  - T.M. to Croker, 1846 July 16; 252087; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Finaly, 1846 December 29; 252086; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, 1847 February 4; 252085; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Hayward, 1847 June 20; 252084; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Corry, 1847 September 12; 252083; ALS
  - T.M. to Monsieur Abbot, n.d.; 252082; ALS
  - T.M. to George W. Austie, n.d.; 252081; ALS
  - T.M. to Doctor Brabant, n.d.; 252080; ALS
  - T.M. to [James] Carpenter, n.d.; 252079; ALS
  - T.M. to [James] Carpenter, n.d.; 252078; ALS
  - T.M. to the Countess of Charlemont, n.d.; 252077; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Charlemont, n.d.; 252076; ALS
  - T.M. to [Lady Holland], 252075; ALS
  - T.M. to Lady Holland, 252074; ALS
  - T.M. to Miss Susan Hughes, n.d.; 252073; ALS
  - T.M. to Longman, n.d.; 252072; ALS
  - T.M. to Mr. Richard [Milliken], n.d.; 252071; ALS
  - T.M. to John Murray, n.d.; 252070; ALS
  - T.M. to Thomas Phillips, n.d.; 252069; ALS
  - T.M. to S. Morrey, n.d.; 252068; ALS
  - T.M. to [Rolls], n.d.; 252067; ALS
  - T.M. to H.D. Scott, n.d.; 252066; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Rev. Sydney Smith, n.d.; 252065; ALS
  - T.M. to [John] Starkey, n.d.; 252064; ALS
  - T.M. to Mrs. Willis, n.d.; 252063; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252062; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252061; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252060; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252059; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252058; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252057; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252056; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252055; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252054; ALS
  - Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252053; ALS
  - Letter Fragments (7); Signed and Unsigned, 252052; AL(S)
  - Miscellaneous Envelopes (8), 1831-1844; 252051
  - "Epistles, Odes and Other Poems by Thomas Moore"; Pages 1, 2, 3, 14, 17, 18, 36, 37, 38 of a series of newspaper articles, [1806 July]; 252050; Clipping
  - "Artists' Benevolent Fund"; article in newspaper, 252049; Clipping
  - Regarding Moore's works, including magazine article on Moore, n.d.; 252048; Clipping
  - Photocopies of engravings and portraits of Thomas Moore; copies of engravings of Sloperton Cottage and Moore's Birthplace, 252047
  - Edward Foss to Thomas Moore, 1811 September 16; 252046; ALS
  - Robert Balmanno to Thomas Moore, 1826 March 26; 252045; ALS
  - [Lord Byron] to Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252044; AL
  - Anna A. Moore letter; Addressee Unknown, 1855 July 12; 252043; ALS
  - S.C. Hall to D.F. MacCarthy, [1879 May 3]; 252042; ALS
  - Ellen Moore to Mrs. Pardey, [n.d. April 13]; 252041; ALS
  - Wm. L. Bowles to Rev. Hall, n.d.; 252040; ALS
  - Bessy Moore to Mrs. Hall, n.d.; 252039; ALS
  - Ellen Moore to P.T. Legle (3 letters), n.d.; 252038; ALS
  - Ellen Moore letter; Addressee Unknown, n.d.; 252037; ALS
  - Unidentified Note about Moore, n.d.; 252036; N
  - "Far, far away, Bewilding World," by Thomas Moore, 1819 May 6; 252035; AMs
  - "A silence follow'd this sweet lay...," by Thomas Moore, [1825]; 252034; AMs
  - "Oh for a tongue to curse the slave...," by Thomas Moore, 1831 July 29; 252033; AMs
  - "Song from the Anthology," by Thomas Moore, [1831 August 15]; 252032; AMs
  - "To the Poet," by Thomas Moore, [1843]; 252031; AMs
  - "Cantus Hibernici, Auctore Thomas Moore", n.d.; 252030; TMs
  - "And doth not a meeting like this...," by Thomas Moore, 252029; AMs
  - 3 poems: (1) Hall of my Sires'...; (2) The High born Ladye; (3) I tell thus, when twilight gleam'd, n.d.; 252028; Mss
  - No. 8; Has Love to that soul so tender..., 252027; AMs
  - "Here, while the moon-light dim...," by Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252026; AMs
  - "Like the gale that sighs along...," by Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252025; AMs
  - "The Living Dog and the Dead Lion" by Thomas Moore, 252024; AMs
  - "Love is a hunter-boy," by Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252023; AMs
  - No. 5; "No, not more Welcome," by Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252022; AMs
  - "Oh! linger yet, nor take the soul...," by Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252021; AMs
  - "Reason and Folly and Beauty," by Thomas Moore, 252020; AMs
  - "A voyager passant sa vie...," by Thomas Moore, n.d.; 252019; AMs
  - "A Pastoral Ballad," by John Bull, [1827 March 12]; 252018; AMs
  - "A Late Scene at Swanage," Author Anonymous, 1827 September; 252017; AMs
- Series III: Numbered copies, 251948 (Box 2)
  - Thomas Moore to Joseph Dennie - see also #99, 1804 July 2; [91]; 252015; ALS
  - T.M. to Joseph Dennie - incl. #91, 1804 September 29; [99]; 252014; ALS
  - T.M. to John Erskine Douglas, 1809 January 14; [164]; 252013; ALS
  - T.M. to Lord Holland, 1811 April; [184]; 252012; ALS
  - T.M. to James Carpenter, 1812 November; [268]; 252011; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1813 January; [286]; 252010; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1814 September 13; [396]; 252009; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1815 May 30; [435]; 252008; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1816 February 12; [460]; 252007; ALS
  - T.M. to Francis Jeffrey, 1816 May 23; [468]; 252006; ALS
  - T.M. to John E. Hall, 1816 June; [471]; 252005; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1817 January 8; [485]; 252004; ALS
  - Thomas Moore to Lady Holland, 1817 July; [504]; 252003; ALS
  - T.M. to James Power, 1817 December 11; [521]; 252002; ALS
  - T.M. to Locke, Hughes and Co., 1818 January 15; [529]; 252001; ALS
  - T.M. to John E. Hall - see #471, 1818 July 12; [554]; 252000; ALS